ANKITH DEEKOLLU | BUSINESS ANALYST

1044 Isle Ct Westerville, OH 43082 | 614-956-9338

ankithdeekollu@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankith-deekollu-227315208/

https://adeekollu.github.io/react-portfolio/



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-oriented and problem solver with 5 years of experience in financial data business analysis and project management. Servant leader highly skilled in communication, collaboration, and technical documentation. Domain knowledge in Finance, Insurance, Health Care, Sales and Marketing

- CORE COMPETENCIES
- ✓ JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- ✓ Bootstrap, jQuery
- ✓ SQL/MySQL and NoSQL/MongoDB
- ✓ ORM/ODM (Sequelize and Mongoose)
- ✓ Full Stack Development and Database Management
- ✓ Familiarity with NPM Libraries and JSON
- ✓ Agile leadership/Scrum Master
- Preparing User Stories, Feature List and Grooming Sessions
- Experience in working with end users and user acceptance testing
- Good working knowledge in JIRA and Confluence
- ✓ Very comfortable in working in an Agile Methodology of project implementation.

- Experience with Git version control
- ▼ Third-Party/Server-Side APIs
- Experience building REST APIs
- ✓ Insomnia/Postman tool for testing and validating RESTful applications
- ✓ Test driven development JEST Framework
- ✓ MVC (model-view-controller) framework
- ✓ Node.js, Python
- Express.js, React.js
- ✓ Visual Studio Code and Chrome Dev Tools
- ✓ GraphQL and Apollo Server
- Data Visualization experience
- Preparing Business Requirement
 Documents, Functional Design Documents,
 facilitating business-IT interactions and
 communications

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mass Technologies Project Manager | March 2020-Current Date Roles & Responsibilities:

- User Stories and Sprint Planning
- Work on User Acceptance Criteria and User Acceptance Testing for critical care systems
- Work with medical and clinical engineering teams in business requirements gathering, functional requirements gathering, created the documents, worked with development teams
- Work closely with business in understanding the business, and how the equipment downtime effects the critical care
- Analyze historical data which is not well organized to find patterns for maintenance windows for least disruptive time for clinical operations.

Penn Mutual/21st Century Financial Financial Business Data Analyst | April 2018 - February 2020 Roles & Responsibilities:

- Worked with business to collect financial data reporting requirements
- Wrote user stories, acceptance criteria, worked in sprint planning
- Worked with development and testing teams through the build, test and UAT phases to ensure that all deliverables are in line with business objectives
- Worked with Business Intelligence team in drafting wireframes for the dashboards
- Worked on end-to-end data mapping along with business and IT teams
- Worked with business on functional requirements collection, worked in tandem with Business Analyst in finalizing the Functional Requirements Document and getting the business sign-off
- Helped the business in basic testing of the metrics and facts using SQL tools for quick prototyping of the metrics and dimensions
- Worked in tandem with Business Intelligence team in visualizations
- Worked on financial risk analysis and risk mitigation
- Worked on What If Analysis on different financial products

New York Life Marketing/Sales Analyst | August 2016 - February 2018

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Worked with business in identifying and creating customer segments
- Customer acquisition and Customer Retention
- Target Market Optimization
- Prospect potential leads and develop financial portfolio forecast
- Generate data analysis reports to understand performance results and optimize on data driven targeting and reach
- A/B testing and what-if analysis.

CERTIFICATIONS

January 2023 | Certificate of Completion from The Ohio State University Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

July 2022 | AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification

November 2021 | Certified Scrum Master (PSM-1 certified)

EDUCATION

2012-2016 | The University of South Wales Bachelor of Arts - Accounting and Finance

2005-2009 | Thomas Worthington High School